Reading Task
The Open Hand, a Universal Sign
When meeting people at the airport, most people smile and shake hands with people they meet.
We know that a smile is usually a sign that people feel friendly
and happy, but what if we don't know who the new person is?
What if we are not introduced by a friend?
What if we are meeting a stranger in an unfamiliar place?
Sometimes people are dangerous and humans have to find ways to protect themselves.
We have to make sure we can trust people we do not know,
and we have to show that we are not dangerous.
Showing Our hands means that we are not armed.
In many cultures today, the Western custom of shaking hands is used.
We use our right hand, which is usually stronger than the left one.
If we are using our hand this way,
it cannot be holding a knife or a gun.
It shows that we trust the other person,
and that the other person can trust us.
Not all cultures use the handshake,
and people in many Asian cultures do not always touch another person.
The traditional greeting in China was to cover the left hand
with the right and bow.
In India, Hindu people join their hands in front of their faces
and bow their heads.
A Muslim will touch his heart, mouth and forehead(额) to show respect.
Even young people in the West now give each other the "high five",
when they slap(拍) each other's hands high in the air.
They are all keeping their hands busy.
In almost all cultures, to smile and show an open right hand means, "
Welcome, you are safe with me.